ah that's what my daddy meant when he
said it's gonna hurt me more it's gonna
hurt you
see my old school y'all I believe in
disciplining my kids I believe in spare
the rod spoil the child so sometimes in
my house it gets physical my sons are
bigger than me so sometimes it gets real
physical last week he got physical and I
think I pulled something I was sore for
three days I said ah that's what my
daddy meant when he said it's gonna hurt
me more it's gonna hurt you
and I come from a strong Christian
background at my house we have the Bible
on DVD a DVD of the Bible so my kids do
something wrong I make them sit down and
watch when Abraham was gonna sacrifice
Isaac and I pause it right before the
land come and I make him go to bed
[Applause]
life moves so fast y'all I remember when
they were little now two getting bigger
my son my youngest son is the most
polite disrespectful child in the world
the light disrespectful he's you don't
curse he's not rude he disrespects you
with proven facts been doing it his
whole life remember he was little took
him to a friend's house he was like that
kind of hungry
all right Willie would get something to
eat and my friend overheard him he said
hey little buddy you want some neat I
got something you all saw he said no
thank you sir you have roaches and
roaches carry germs I'll just wait so
I'll go home
you do have roaches man he at that age
now where he wants to do what his
friends do hey Dad can I get the new
iPhone I said you got some new iPhone
money no that's why I'm asking you
well I guess you're gonna use that old
Android hi dad
what can I hang out with my friends yeah
hang out with the friends but call me at
8:30 okay dad
8:30 comes no call 9:30 comes no call he
walking house at 10 o'clock
upside his head immediately to establish
dominance in my own right hey man then I
tell you called me at 8:30 dad I didn't
call you cuz my phone died when you with
your friends don't take our phones don't
they got charges well yeah dad they got
the new iPhone I got this old Android
the charger won't even fit if they had
they phone and they had day charges why
didn't you call me from they thought
well dad I didn't call you from a phone
cuz I don't know your number
I know Mama's number but yours is just a
speed dial just go to bed he got me
again
cuz I don't know his number either
the light disrespectful I remember he
was the only black kid in his class the
only one I was proud at the open house
cuz the kids did self-portraits and I
immediately knew which one my son was
now the beautiful thing about these
pictures was each kid got to put one
thing they loved at the bottom of the
picture little Shelby had I love Barbie
little Josh had I love soccer my son a
little ray-ray bottom his picture I love
chicken he didn't know he didn't know
but he did get a gold star yes he did
this is definitely gonna be an away game
[Applause]
somewhat jokes are just throwing out
their stuff for you to catch him I'm not
gonna work extra hard oh gosh this is
crazy I was having a bad day y'all never
have a day so bad that you call one of
your friends that you know was doing
worse than you so you feel better about
your situation I called my friend I was
like hey man you get that job he said
nah I say good good you should get a
tattoo on your face you'll stand out in
interviews I'm glad y'all laughing I
don't cuz right now as a country we in a
bad place cuz we so divided everybody
divided all because of an election
I learned something Donald Trump is 70
years old and Hillary Clinton is 70
years old I'll call my grandma I say
grandma is jobs out there if you series
[Laughter]
just consider the rockatuer looking kill
grandma get out there and do something
you ain't raised us like that too much
information in the news yo kids watch
the news they know what's going on in
the world I saw some kids outside
playing Ebola yes
you got Ebola oh yes man oh but you the
head no it sure is I called Obamacare
Obamacare I recently moved kind of
depressing
I could have moved to a bad place but
everything I own fit inside a truck that
cost $19.99 and they offer me the
insurance for $9.99 it's just one worth
it and my new neighbor is a thug but he
homeschoolers kids so every morning the
outside playing I don't know if they
skipped my school today on recess
and I'm just too scared to ask this year
is flying by y'all I said I'm a complete
things that I started last year I
started an after-school program for kids
what he can come and do their homework
yes
yeah thank you I serve Chinese food I
called it home walk Samba jokes I just
throw them out there so for you catch
you I am uh be honest with you I started
this whole comedy thing because the NBA
one interested this I'm five
five-and-a-half that's not the funny
part
[Laughter]
women say things that mean that they'll
say to other men they say stuff like oh
you Sookie a grown man why would you say
that to me cuz everything is cute with
us don't tell me if you was taller you
would be so so hint I said if your hair
was longer using better shape you would
be Beyonce and it never fails after show
somebody always walk up to me to pat me
on the back
good job big man now I'm excited and
confused at the same time kind of big
for a little man kind of like a jumbo
shrimp
or a megabyte that's like me giving
false hope to a blind man
hey Ryan think I'll be able to see you
again yeah we'll just play it by ear and
that made me fake who cleans up after
seeing eye dogs
I'm at that point my life with my family
making me do stuff they forced me to get
a cat I hate cats cats and jerks don't
care what you say I can't stand them and
it's a rescue cat so you off the streets
so I don't trust them no he's still got
his claws it's like I live with a felon
with a firearm
the cats are so condescending they look
at you like they don't trust you in your
own house it's not a cabbie looking at
you whenever I leave you get on my side
of the bed and you look at hey you know
when you leave imma be cuddling with
your wife oh I'll get a cat if you have
a dog and you see the glass down man's
best friend might take a sip out your
water you'd be upset you be like you
know what my best friend just took a sip
out of my water what you gonna do let me
tell you how much of a jerk just caddy
is this is what the cat did in my water
[Laughter]
and I think he just came out the litter
box cuz my water tasted crunchy that was
very upset to y'all when you mad you
make other people mad you don't try to
it just happens I went to my doctor's
office I asked him who his doctor was
and then I switch doctors
and went to the mall I saw a family the
whole family was ugly say dang even the
best-looking person in a family it's
like being the valedictorian in a GED
program and every time I go to the mall
I always get an application no matter
what store I go in I get an application
people think I'm crazy
when I leave them all and people in the
parking lot begging for spare change
I'll just go
[Music]
[Applause]
you can use me as a reference
let me formally introduce myself my name
is Ron but my first name is spelled
different this spell are a H in yes my
mother was Trivedi first day of school
money it was always like a question dang
these black kids pick up my favorite
rock now listen if you're running for
class president but we don't need to see
your birth certificate
[Laughter]
I got a website y'all make sure you
check me out Ryan Horton calm I linked
the Twitter's on there my link to
Facebook cuz everybody's on Facebook
my mama's on Facebook my Grandmama's on
Facebook my bill collectors are on
Facebook they keep poking me I keep
ignoring them they actually scan my
bills and tag me in the pictures my mama
gonna comment yeah he owe me too and
then she liked it
are you gonna like your own comment that
is so selfish it do me a favor y'all
email call Tex all your black friends I
think is appropriate they participate in
Farmville
nothing fun about firemen y'all got us
the first time and if you send me a
farmville request I will treat it as a
hate crime
the prosecute to the fullest extent of
the law
okay older people Facebook is this thing
on your computer your computer kind of
like your typewriter but with the TV
screen on it I always talk about older
people not cuz I don't like you I just
don't trust you Oh people are slick you
say hi then they say hi you know talking
to him for like two hours about how a
loaf of bread used to cost a nickel the
old people would say anything to you and
you have to respect it you have to
respect your elders
this old man gonna tell me excuse me
young man I said yes sir
he said I love what you did to your hair
so well well thank you sir so yes it's
very nice but do you wash it once a day
as a face or twice a week is here
[Laughter]
once there's a face sir
I was in the grocery store this old man
sends them to me I know how to respond
y'all I had no comeback I've pushed him
a card I said excuse me sir he said oh
no you have just as much right to be
here as me why thank you Abraham Lincoln
feels great to shop at a newly
desegregated Walmart
you got the brown bread buy the white
bread thank you so so much son thank you
I am a happily married man
thank you yes my wife is my better half
Ryan you better do this and you better
do that
you see my best friend good that's what
she told me
I married my high school sweetheart yeah
and yeah thank you love is real and the
wedding was so special because our
oldest son was in it put a ring on it yo
we have four kids three sons and a
daughter we kept trying for that little
girl so she kind of like the princess of
the house when I say princess I mean be
careful what you wish for
I was smoking and observing can you tell
me daddy said what baby you know back
and your stomach ain't the same no more
see what she said well your back go like
this and your stomach go like that so
shut up your mama like it she said no
she da no she down
no we talked about it she said you need
to do some sit-ups I can't do none with
her I can't take her nowhere cuz she too
knows he took her to Walmart we saw a
man dressed like a lady
immediately she had to investigate
[Music]
[Laughter]
excuse me mister ma'am I know he's
supposed to talk to strangers but them
shoes is cute that's very sensitive
y'all I remember when I found out my
daughter had to wear hearing aids very
shocked very upset I actually cried
about it I thought about all the time I
wasted yelling
[Laughter]
gonna have one of my sons bringing me
the remote and I thought you'd be
ashamed of the hearing aids but she
loves the hearing aids she loves him oh
my god daddy I love these hearing aids I
get the birds chirping I get water
flowing I get all my music daddy I just
love them I'm like wow that's amazing
but you know what she's still a kid
sometimes she's just hard-headed so if I
tell her to do something and she don't
do it I get very upset hey didn't ask
you to clean up your room
didn't I tell you to put a little dishes
you know what you know what give me the
hearing aids if you ain't gonna listen
to me you're gonna listen to nobody stop
crying
look at me when I'm talking to you these
are just jokes don't nobody call the
people on me right
these are just jokes I promise you're
gonna ask her but you don't have to
spray them real loud
I am a very special child my parent
not that kind of special man my parents
was married as teenagers I was born to
teenage parents sometimes I think my
mother's still mad at me cuz I got her
grounded my mother and father were very
very young so didn't work out so I can't
tell you a lot about him I know he was
an athlete so he was a fierce competitor
I'll all his friends he was the best at
hide-and-go-seek
[Laughter]
mother actually got remarried when I was
very young so I was blessed to have a
father in my life I had two fathers have
a biological father and I was stepfather
my biological father I'll call pops cuz
he wasn't around it kind of popped up at
nine in my stepfather I called dad
because he the one who actually raised
me ironically both of their names is
Robert tell the job my mama be trippin
on she talkin to give him both the same
amount of respect so on holidays I'll
get him both the same team Jersey with
Robert on the back but one was home and
one was away
[Laughter]
[Applause]
it was a Padres jersey
yup big sports fans here big sports fans
see I just got nervous I get nervous
around sports fans they get too real
I saw some Yankees fans physically fight
some Red Sox fans they're never that
series yellow you see round horny with a
team jersey home don't mean I follow the
team it means it matches my shoes right
this force feelings go all-out they
paint a face that dress up like the
mascot it's kind of cool until you lose
then you got a ride home looking stupid
and then the other team always give you
an insult
wrapped in a compliment a good game poor
coaching you almost had us you gave a
good effort and they smack you on the
booty so whenever I see one of those big
monster trucks with the gun rack and
Confederate flag I say good game for a
coaching you almost had us you gave a
good effort
when I smack him on the booty
[Applause]
don't none a detective like a little
black news smacking well buddy you got a
truck like that these are just jokes I
will not be snacking on your booty huh
Oh life moves so fast y'all I remember
when I was young and I made the football
team yes I made the football team so
proud y'all kept my uniform on helmet on
mouthpiece in nobody knew what I was
singing but I was proud I came home one
day my dad's standing outside we had
that father-to-son moment he's like a
man you're getting older what are you
planning on doing for the rest of your
life I said dad I'm pretty good at this
football thing I think I'm gonna go pro
he looked me right nods and said you
need to pick something else I didn't get
to what's your backup plan son or what
if you get hurt dude that guy you need
to pick something else so as a teenager
just made me so mad y'all I don't know
why he didn't believe in me
right I went to that school I practiced
harder than everybody else on that team
see I was what you call a flanker a lot
of people know what a flanker is a
flanker is kind of like a running back
this last receiver and at my school that
meant that everybody made the team so
whatever so I was so much better than
the other third stringer that I got my
own play I will come out the backfield
turn left fake right the ball be right
there to coast Aron you ready to run
your play I said coach I stay ready he
said all right let's do it
I lined up in the backfield had my game
face on
they hype the ball I'm all fast like a
cheetah all right a black panther I
think left turn right as soon as the
ball hit my hand I open my eyes and
everybody was standing over said wait
hold on to the ball right wait hold on
to the ball and it freaked me out
because I I really didn't hold on to the
ball you hit me so hard that my body
just locked up right I don't know how
long I was out but my house is 23
minutes away from the school and my
daddy was telling me said I told you to
pick something else
I picked something else you're doing
comedy we get to travel all over the
place y'all I went to a Connecticut they
put me in this fancy hotel called
America's best value you ever heard of
this hotel this should be called
Baghdad's mediocre at best it looked
like a crime scene from first 48 and
they had a roaches no big roaches it was
a roach so big you look like a Snickers
on the ground and it had them big long
antennas moving like the matrix I got
ready step on the right two antenna
touch my leg yeah yeah ran ice cream
that wasn't ready right
so I said yo I need to show the
management that they have a problem so
what I did was I took a glass and I put
it on top of the roach
immediately the roach got that snitching
on the other roaches they always missing
on first 48 you only got cable
true story yeah for ten years of my life
I did pest control and I'm scared of
bugs but that was my motivation I'm
gonna tell you I'm scared a bug yeah I
will never forget it I was in a Kmart
walking down the dog food aisle it was a
moth it was flying I tried to swat it
out the way the moth flew in my ear yeah
oh my goodness have you ever had some
flying you're here it is so loud it
sound like a helicopter in my hair and
you can feel it like crawling on the
inside and I didn't know what to do so I
did they called the paramedics they
called them they rushed in with the
gurney as soon as I sat down the moth
flew out my ear
I said thank goodness is gone and his
old man was walking by he said yeah but
what if he laid eggs and you here so I
don't trust old people I'm telling you
comedy comedy comedy oh we get to go all
over the place I went to uh Birmingham
Alabama I got off the plane and this
lady asked me what I was doing in town I
said ma'am I'm an entertainer she said
are you Darius Rucker I know it was I
had to google it
that's Hootie from Hootie and the
Blowfish
so I looked at it I was like well he
black and i'm black and she weighs
uh-huh yes I do look a little whoo
[Laughter]
but if somebody say you look like
somebody you got to find out if they
ugly or not I said excuse me ma'am is
hoody ugly to you no he is very handsome
I said Rock Me mama like a rock anyway I
had to google that too because that was
I go like yeah when I first walked out
here I was like man this is love white
people it's cool I love white people I
have a white uncle be the black sheep in
his family
cellphones are tricky Oh Oh everybody
cell phone you got a picture of somebody
you love as your screensaver I got a
picture of my wife this lady I know she
saw the picture she said is that your
wife I said yes it is she said I'm sorry
I owe you an apology like an apology
it's like no no no I thought you had a
white wife why would you apologize if I
had a white wife so now I'm upset and
what am i doing that makes you think I
had a white wife right so now I'm heated
I'm about to go off y'all like upset up
to here with it right and then I thought
about it I was like oh she knows I'm in
entertain me
[Laughter]
that was too much for you a pout
be my wife been together for 20 years
thank you 22 years and we've got so long
William Harvey in the war when she get
mad at me she do real real subtle stuff
she pick out my clothes last week's
picked up with them real tight muscle
shirts for me to wear I got no muscles
y'all I was on stage there like a real
strong ethiopian y'all may not notice
but your black family we like to put
lotion on for we leave the house she
don't give me this lotion this smell
good smell great
it had glitter in it I'm on stage than
like a little black disco ball gay dudes
trying to highlight me after the show
use up their shine
you'd ever gonna be a superstar Oh
twinkle twinkle superstar 20 years y'all
I know a little bit about relationships
any single ladies in here single ladies
you hear that fellas you hear that huh
don't be fooled by that man do your
research before you fall in love don't
meet their mamas I'm serious if they
mama look like a grizzly bear I don't
care how cute earth Selene is to you she
is a grizzly cub everything is cute when
it's little you complain about she too
big no she's not she's a perfect size
for a grizzly bear her age
my friend was dating the big girl you
she had a weight problem because she was
following McDonald's on Twitter her
phone kept going off but up up up see
I'm learning in relationships fellas we
don't we don't give like they give but
we just we just let stuff go you gotta
communicate that's where the breakdown
is we'll give you some examples man if
if your woman is mad you have two
choices
let her be mad or let her be mad
I just saved some of y'all right now I
just saved you my wife don't even do
social media don't even do it although
she do participate in throwback
Thursdays no but she brings up something
I did in the past and I get to the next
week to defend myself now having a wife
is a blessing it really is if are you
lucky and you blessed have a beautiful
lady by your side take a second right
now take a look at her look at me
blessed you are blessed did you know she
don't live longer than you did you know
that they live longer than us man don't
nobody know why I don't know why but I
know what I'm gonna do I'm gonna do
whatever she does if she used oil of
olay I'm using oil of olay
she eats best okay I'm heating Special K
I'm not going dying she live a good life
after me not on my watch me my wife got
into a little disagreement found out she
went to the grocery store and she
brought some vitamins oh we take advice
so I took some of the vitamins and I let
her know hey you know what kind of
disappointed
I found your stash she's like what is
you talking about I said the vitamins I
found them I'm hurt you don't even know
who you are no more
she said Ryan knows ain't vitamins those
are perfect control
fellas you ever do something so stupid
you don't have an answer but as a man
you have to apply all I can say is well
I don't want no more kids either we
don't take these together because we're
family
that's what we do
[Applause]
you